Guide to the Stanford News Service Audiovisual Recordings SC1125
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Videorecordings, 1936-2011; Series 2
  - James Doty, MD, CCare, Dalai Lama, + B-Roll, 2010-10-12; 10-1012-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 54)
    James Doty, director and founder of the Center for Compassion and Altruism Research and Education, spoke with the Dalai Lama, Tenzin Gyatso, about “The Centrality of Compassion in Human Life and Society". Gyatso repeatedly stressed a secular approach to compassion that reaches beyond individual creeds and beliefs. He spoke of the need for mutual respect and friendship, the care and education of children, and ongoing dialogue for conflict resolution.
  - Dalai Lama, Maples Pavilion, 2010-10-14; 10-1014-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 54)
  - Dalai Lama, Maples Pavilion, 2010-10-14; 10-1014-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 56)
  - Dalai Lama, Memorial Church, 2010-10-14; 10-1014-2a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 56)
    The Dalai Lama presents thе 2010 Rathbun Lecture, “Harry’s Last Lecture on a Meaningful Life” sharing his reflections on how tο lead a fulfilling life οf purpose and moral values. Hе focuses on how one сan bе a valuable member οf society and life a live filled with compassion even in the modern world.
  - Dalai Lama, Memorial Church, 2010-10-14; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 47)
  - Graphic Novel, Social Change, Pika-Don, 2010-10-20; 10-1020-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 49)
    Stanford students collaborate in "comics journalism" – producing books on contemporary social issues. This year's book, 'Pika-Don,' tells the story of the man who survived the atomic bombing of both Hiroshima and Nagasaki. This is part of the Stanford Graphic Novel Project. Cambridge-educated Dan Archer, a Knight journalism fellow at Stanford, is the art director for the project.
  - Graphic Novel, Social Change, Pika-Don, B-Roll of Book, 2010-10-20; 10-1020-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 49)
    Stanford students collaborate in "comics journalism" – producing books on contemporary social issues. This year's book, 'Pika-Don,' tells the story of the man who survived the atomic bombing of both Hiroshima and Nagasaki. This is part of the Stanford Graphic Novel Project. Cambridge-educated Dan Archer, a Knight journalism fellow at Stanford, is the art director for the project. Tape contains B-roll of the book.
  - Mark Schnitzer, Mice Research, 2010-10-26; 10-1026-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 49)
    "Mark Schnitzer, associate professor of biology and of applied physics, and other Stanford scientists have devised a new method that not only lets them peer deep inside the brain to examine its neurons but also allows them to continue monitoring for months. Tiny glass tubes, about half the width of a grain of rice, are carefully placed in the deep brain of an anaesthetized mouse. Once the tubes are in place, the brain is not exposed to the outside environment, thus preventing infection. When researchers want to examine the cells and their interactions at this site, they insert a tiny optical instrument called a microendoscope inside the glass guide tube. The guide tubes have glass windows at the ends through which scientists can examine the interior of the brain."
  - Zero Gravity, Student Satellites, 2010-10-26; 10-1026-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 49)
    "Stanford researchers have completed the first successful tests in zero gravity of a canopy for CubeSats – the tiny satellites that hitch rides on rockets sending larger satellites into orbit. The goal is to gather data on what happens when micrometeoroids slam into a satellite. Nicolas Lee and fellow graduate students Shandor Dektor and Joseph Johnson recently tested their canopies in zero gravity aboard a NASA-hire airplane flying over the Gulf of Mexico."
  - Paula Fredriksen, 2010-10-28; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - LA Theaterworks Pentagon Papers Discussion, 2010-10-29 (Box 46)
  - Clooney, Prendergast, Sudan, 2010-11-08; 10-1108-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 49)
    "George Clooney and activist John Prendergast put a spotlight on the volatility threatening to spark more genocide in Sudan at Cubberley Auditorium. Worried that widespread violence will ravage Africa's largest country after voters cast ballots in a January referendum that is likely to split the country in two, Clooney and Prendergast are waging a campaign to get the United States and the international community to help pave the way for a peaceful transition. During the event moderated by Stephen Stedman – a political scientist and senior fellow at the Freeman Spogli Institute – the duo took questions from the audience and a panel of Stanford members of STAND, a student anti-genocide group that helped sponsor the gathering."
  - Clooney, Prendergast, Sudan, 2010-11-08; 10-1108-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 49)
  - Aurora Forum "Iraq Refram", 2010-11-12 (Box 46)
  - Alarm Will Sound post-concert talk with John Adams at Dinkelspiel, 2010-11-30 (Box 46)
  - Conch at Peru's Chavín, 2011-01-13; 11-0113-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 49)
    "Stanford archaeologists are working with acousticians to determine why the pre-Incan residents of Chavín de Huántar used conches and the effects that they had with the unique acoustics in their temples. In July 2001, Stanford archaeologists working at Chavín's 3,000-year-old ceremonial center came across a conch buried in the dirt in one of the temple's underground galleries. To get a sense of the scale of the discovery, remember that only a couple of decorated conches had ever before been found in Peru."
  - PAC Lecture: Lec Raine, 2011-03-10 (Box 46)
  - PACS Seminar by Susan Sturm, 2011-03-31 (Box 46)
  - An Evening with Stpehen Foster at Cubberly Auditorium, 2011-10-11; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 46)
  - Medieval Matters - Anthony Grafton, 2011-11-02 (Box 46)
  - Bijan Ghelby, 2011-11-09 (Box 46)
  - Iranian Studies, 2012-04-19 (Box 46)
  - "Nuclear Security or Insecurity" and "Whispers of Big Bang", undated; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 46)
  - Soit Podcast Producer, undated (Box 46)
  - Stanford Forum on Terorrism, ZZ0241; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 45)
  - Master Dunbar DVD 07 (Box 46)
  - Panel 1, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - Kresege Audotrium, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - Master Dumbar Performance 01, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - Master Dunbar Performance 02, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - Master Dunbar Performance 03 (Box 46)
  - Master Dunbar Peformance 04 (Box 46)
  - Master Dunbar Performance 05 (Box 46)
  - Master Dunbar Performance 06 (Box 46)
  - Cubberly auditorum, 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 46)
  - Memorial Auditorium Panel 1, 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 46)
  - Memorial Auditorium Panel 2, 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 46)
  - Master Dunbar DVD 08, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - Master Dunbar DVD 09, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - Master Dunbar DVD 01, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - Uncommon Knowledge Taylor/Judd + Steele (Box 46)
  - We the People: Islam & U.S. politics, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - Panel 2, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - Energy crossroads events, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - Cubberley, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - Kresge, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - Uncommon Knowledge, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - Uncommon Knowledge, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - T.J. Rogers & Tom Wolfe, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 46)
  - Ms. at 40 - Panel, 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 46)
  - Dorfmon Lecture by Susan Lindquist (Box 46)
  - eHuman iTunesU (Box 46)
  - Anatomy Heart (Box 46)
  - Carii Ayer on Rott U.2.O. (Box 46)
  - Soit V2 Handouts (Box 46)
  - GSB S180, 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 46)
  - Some Small Dive by Mark Robinson (Box 46)
  - The Stanford Soundtrack Volume 8 (Box 46)
  - Medival Matters Disc 1 (Box 46)
  - Medival Matters Disc 2 (Box 46)
  - "The Arts at Stanford: The Big Picture" by Megan Miller (Box 46)
  - Barnes, McDowell, Cranston, 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 46)
  - GSB S181, 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 46)
  - Office of Development Investment Conference, 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 46)
  - Iranian Studies Houchang Chehabi, 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 46)
  - Iranian Studies Roger Cohen, 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 46)
  - GSB SL82, 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 46)
  - Food Summit (Box 46)
  - InterChange with Condoleezza Rice, Hosted by Jim Bettinger, 1999-05-14; ARCH-2016-110; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 58)
    Rice, Condoleezza